（スー）
見て見て このウエルカムボード
Look at this welcome board!
Their caricature is perfect!
似顔絵 超似てる
（烈子(れつこ)）ほんとだ！ うける
You're right! It's funny.
I still can't believe those two
are tying the knot.
あの２人が結婚するなんて
思わなかったなあ
Yeah. It's a bizarre match, isn't it?
（スー）ねえ 超意外な
組み合わせだよね
じゃあ 受付 済ませちゃおうか
Well, then, shall we finish checking in?
（烈子）うん
OK.
（足音）
この度は おめでとうございます
My congratulations to the bride and groom.
（受付）ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
CONGRATULATIONS
んんっ… 両人との ご関係は！？
How do you know the happy couple?
I'm the bride's friend...
新婦の友人でございます…！
（烈子）ご祝儀の相場は３万円！
The expected amount
for a wedding gift is 30,000 yen!
My blood and tears
have taken form as 30,000 yen!
私の血と涙が しみこんだ３万円！
Honestly, I don't want to give it away.
正直 渡したくない！
渡したくない！
I don't want to give it away!
Get your dirty paws off my money!
RAGE
♪～
～♪
（烈子）
ご祝儀３万円って高すぎない？
Isn't 30,000 yen a bit much
for a wedding gift?
I'll have to tighten
my food budget this month.
今月 食費 削らないと厳しいよ…
（フェネ子(こ)）
うちらの年齢だと きついよね
It's tough at our age.
I just give a flat 20,000 regardless.
私は有無を言わさず
２万で済ませるけど
Maybe I should do that, too.
私も今度から そうしようかな
（カバ恵(え)）駄目よ～
That's no good!
２は偶数で半分に割りきれるから
せっかく くっついた２人が―
Two is an even number
that's easy to split!
It is said that even though a couple
have just got hitched, they will split up!
パッカーンと別れちゃうって
言うでしょ？
それ みんな言いますけど…
So the old wives' tale goes...
Even if you pay 30,000,
some couples separate anyway.
３万払っても別れるやつは別れるし
But ceremonies cost
a lot of money and work, you know!
でも実際 式って
お金かかって大変なのよお…
ブライダル産業を
肥え太らせるだけの方便
That's what the bridal industry
wants you to think.
Another day in the accounting department
has begun.
（烈子）また今日も
経理部での一日が始まる
（トン）
俺は たった今から お前を…
As of now,
I've got a new name for you.
ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT
（トン）腰掛けえええええ！
Short-timer!
（烈子）
オヨビデスカ トンブチョウ
You called, Director Ton?
午後までに この伝票整理やっとけ
Sort out these expense forms
by this afternoon.
あと これと！ これと！
これの入力な！
Then these!
And these!
And input these!
（烈子）ハイ カシコマリマシタ
Yes. As you wish.
（坪根(つぼね)）烈子さ～ん
Miss Retsuko?
Yes, ma'am?
（烈子）オヨビデスカ
オーッホッホッホッ…
随分 かわいげが
出てきたんじゃな～い？
What a splendid change in attitude!
私に たてついてきた あなたとは
別人みたい
You're like a different person
to the one who talked back to me.
お手
Shake!
ハウス！
House!
オーッホッホッホッ…
何て いい子
Good girl!
That's what happens
when you turn the screws a little.
ちょっと きゅうを据えてやりゃ
こんなもんよ 見ろ
Look! Look at that face.
It's brimming with delight for work.
あの労働の喜びに満ちた
すがすがしい顔を！
こき使いがいが あるわねえ
It's worth pushing her to work harder.
烈子
Retsuko.
こないだ トン部長に呼び出されて
何か言われたの？
What happened when Director Ton
called you out?
Private chats during work are prohibited.
キンムチュウハ
シゴ ゲンキンデス
駄目だ こりゃ
This is bad.
WATER
（烈子の飲む音）
（烈子）プハー
おうち帰りたい…
I wanna go home!
あっ いつもの烈子だ
Oh, she's snapped out of it.
（ハイ田(だ)）
干しシイタケみたいなやつだな
She's like a shriveled-up mushroom.
What's up with you?
最近どうした？ 真面目 通り越して
まるでロボットだぞ
You've gone past serious
to acting like a robot.
おい 腰掛け！ このドリアン
鼻の穴に詰めとけ！
Hey, Short-timer!
Stick this durian up your nose!
カシコマリマシタ
Certainly, sir.
いや～ まあ
いろいろありまして…
Well... I guess...
A lot has happened.
先週 坪根さんに
１発 食らわせた勢いは―
What happened to the Retsuko
that let Miss Tsubone have it last week?
どうしたんだよ？
Huh?
えっ…
どこ行くんだよ？
Where are you going?
（烈子）落ち着けるとこ
Somewhere to calm down.
ARCHIVE ROOM
（烈子）うら若き乙女が―
A girl with dreams,
パンの耳にマヨネーズを付けて
かじる午後
reduced to eating bread crusts
dipped in mayo...
（食べる音）
さすがに この姿は
フェネ子たちにも見せられないなあ
I can't let Fenneko or Haida
see me like this.
ハア…
ここ結構 落ち着く
It's quite relaxing here.
（携帯電話の振動音）
もしもし？
Hello?
もう～ ほんと
あいつら マジ信じられない！
I can't believe those guys!
私 悲しくなっちゃってさあ！
I'm devastated!
Not that I didn't see it coming!
そりゃ 全く予想してないわけじゃ
なかったけどお！
Wait, what are you talking about?
（烈子）ちょっと待って 何の話？
I'm sorry for calling like this!
I'm really worked up right now!
ごめんね
いきなり電話しちゃって！
今 超興奮してるから！
てか もう…
I just don't get it!
落ち着いてよ
Calm down.
何の話？
What happened?
（スー）離婚だって
They got divorced!
離婚？
Divorced?
何で！？ 式挙げたばっかじゃん！
Why? They only just got married!
I heard they had a huge fight
at the airport!
（スー）
あのあと 成田(なりた)で 大げんかだって！
帰りなら まだ分かるけど
行きだよ！？
They didn't even make it
to their honeymoon!
やっぱ 愛だけじゃ
乗り越えられなかったんだよ
I knew love wouldn't be enough
for those two!
あの最悪の組み合わせは！
They're from different worlds!
あの組み合わせはね…
They were an odd couple...
ていうか３万！
But wait... 30,000!
（スー）そう ３万！
Yes! 30,000!
３万！
-30,000!
（スー）３万！
２万にしとけばよかった！
Why didn't I give 20,000 yen?
（スー）何言ってんの
200円の価値もないよ！
For their marriage?
It wasn't even worth 200 yen!
もう～ この悲しみを
誰かとシェアしたくてさ！
I just had to share my sadness
with someone!
あ 次 イノコにもかけるから
切るね
Oh, I'm calling Inoko next, so bye.
（通話が切れた音）
あっ
Huh?
あっ ハイ田君
Oh, Mr. Haida.
烈子さん見なかった？
Have you seen Miss Retsuko?
（ハイ田）えっ？ いや…
Oh... No...
見てないすけど
I haven't seen her...
チッ…
つくだ煮の瓶のふたを
開けさせようと思ったのに
I was going to make her
open this jar.
全然 開かないのよ これ！
I can't... open it at all!
俺 開けましょうか？
Shall I open it?
いいの！
That's OK!
あの子に開けさせるから
Because I'm going
to make that girl open it.
フッフッフッ…
アッハッハッハッハ…
烈子 ちゃんと飯 食ったのかな…
I wonder if Retsuko ate a proper lunch.
ん？
何だよ？
What?
心配なのだね
You're worried about her.
あっ？
Hey, wait a minute.
お… おい ちょっと待て
違うぞ 別に そういう意味じゃ…
You're wrong. It doesn't mean that!
Enduring power harassment
from superiors every day...
日々 職場で上司のパワハラに
耐える灰色の日々…
追い詰められた彼女は屋上から…
Having been chased into a corner,
she heads for the roof...
（ハイ田）
ちょちょちょちょちょ… ちょい
Wait! Hey!
おい お前 バカ！
そういうこと言うなって マジで
Don't be stupid! You can't just say that!
捜してくれば？
Go look for her, then.
ん…
Yeah...
ARCHIVE ROOM
（烈子の食べる音）
（烈子）離婚～！？
Divorce?
私が誰のために食費削って
苦労してると思ってんの！？
For whom did I tighten my food budget?
（烈子）
ハア… 私の３万が無駄に…
My 30,000 yen, all wasted.
（烈子）いや！ いつか私が
結婚するときが来たら―
No...
When my time comes to get married...
離婚した２人を式に参列させて
それぞれから３万ずつ―
I'll have them both attend the ceremony.
I'll get 30,000 yen from each of them.
計６万 きっちり倍額 回収して…
I'll double my money to 60,000!
結婚？
Marriage?
結婚…
Marriage...
家庭…
A family...
退職…
Quitting work...
（烈子）専業主婦！
A full-time house wife?
（エコー）
（ベルの音）
（ファンファーレ）
（デス烈子の叫び声）
Matrimonial freedom!
（デス烈子）
見えたあああああああ！
Matrimonial freedom!
ARCHIVE ROOM
（烈子）忘れてた
I forgot.
結婚して
会社を辞めるって手があった！
I could always get married
and quit the company!
私に必要なのは―
What I need
結婚を前提とした彼氏！
is a boyfriend that I can then marry!
烈子！？
Retsuko,
お前 何してたんだよ！？
what were you doing?
何って…
What do you mean?
御飯 食べてただけだよ
I was just eating lunch.
ハア～…
こっちは超心配してたんだぞ？
I was really worried!
Fenneko went to a morbid place...
フェネ子のやつが
変なこと言うから…
ねえ ハイ田君ってさ―
Hey, Haida...
結婚したら奥さんに働いてほしい？
それとも 家にいてほしい？
would you want your wife to work,
or would you want her to stay at home?
えっ！？
Huh?
いや いきなり
そんなこと聞かれても…
That's quite a question...
うーん そうだな…
Let's see...
I guess I'd want her to have a job.
俺は外で働いてほしいかなあ
俺の稼ぎだけじゃ
不安ってのもあるし―
My salary's not the biggest, you see.
それにずっと家にいてもらうよりは
仕事を続けてもらって―
Rather than having her at home all day,
if she continued working,
we'd be a good influence on...
お互いに いい刺激を…
あれっ？
Huh?
烈子！？
Retsuko?
（烈子）そっか そっか
I see, I see.
In other words,
if I got a partner with a good salary,
つまり 稼ぎが十分にある
相手をゲットすれば―
専業主婦になれる確率が
高くなるってことか！
I could probably become
a full-time house wife!
私の人生は―
My life...
まだ終わってない！
is not over yet!
GET A DESIRABLE BODY!
"Get a desirable body
（烈子）“もてるボディを―”
“手に入れる！”
and reel them in."
（角田(つのだ)）え～ 先輩は そのままでも
十分かわいいと思いますけど～
What? But I think you're cute enough
just the way you are.
うーん… でも もう少し
スリムになったほうがいいかなって
I just thought it would be nice
to get a little bit slimmer.
あっ もてたいってことですか！？
Oh, so you're on the prowl!
ああ… いや あの…
Oh, well, you know...
I mean, I just want to be pretty
in a regular way.
普通に きれいに
なりたいっていうか…
あっ 普通に
もてたいってことですか！
Oh! You mean you want to be "regular hot"!
はあ…
Oh...
Well, just in an average way.
まあ… 人並みに
でも～ 先輩って
ぽにゃっとしてるから―
But, that slight chubbiness of yours
見てるほうは何か安心するし―
is what puts people at ease,
二の腕も プニプニっとしてて
赤ちゃんみたいだし―
like those squishy, baby-like arms!
そのままの感じでも
ぜーったい もてますよ～
So you could get a boyfriend if you tried!
（烈子）あれは―
That... obviously means "lose weight",
doesn't it?
明らかに痩せろって意味だよね…
（烈子）うーん…
やっぱ 今日は いいや…
I don't feel like it today...
あっ…
Excuse me!
す… すいません！
（烈子）このフロア
ボディビル教室もあるのかな？
Does this floor
have a body-building class, too?
（先生）プロテイン？
Protein?
What?
えっ？
プロテイン？
Protein?
えっと あの…
ヨガ教室に興味があっただけで…
I... I was only interested
in the yoga class.
テ～イン
...tein...
プロテ～イン！
Protein!
（烈子）
ああっ… あの ごめんなさい！
Oh, I'm sorry!
Bodybuilding is not my thing!
筋肉には興味ないんです！
ヨガ教室に通って痩せたら―
I was just wondering if losing some weight
would make me desirable, that's all!
（足音）
もてるかなって
思っただけなんです！
Teacher, namaste!
（生徒）先生 ナマステ
（生徒）ナマステ
Namaste!
プロテイ～ン
Protein!
（烈子）この人がヨガの先生！？
This guy teaches yoga?
（ゴリ）あら？
（ドアが閉まる音）
プロテイン！
Protein!
えと…
サインしろってことですかね…？
I'm guessing that means "sign here."
（目覚ましの音）
な… なあ 烈子
Hey, Retsuko.
さっき フェネ子と
話したんだけどさ―
I was talking to Fenneko a while ago.
今日 このあと暇？
Are you free tonight?
How about the three of us go for drinks?
したら ３人で飲み行かね？
ごめん！ 用事あるから！
Sorry!
I have plans!
あっ… アハハハハ…
ハハハハハハ…
笑ってんじゃねえよ！
It's not funny!
プロ テイン！ プロ テイン！
-Protein! Protein!
-OK, that's the pigeon pose!
（アシスタント）
はい それがハトのポーズでーす
慣れてない方は
無理しないでくださーい
If you're not used to it yet,
don't force it.
（烈子）
どうして あの２人が ここに？
Why are those two here?
向こうは気付いてないのかな…
Maybe they haven't noticed me...
Good work today!
（生徒）お疲れさまでーす
（生徒）お先 失礼しまーす
I'm heading out now.
（烈子）超見てくるし
これ絶対 気付いてるじゃん
They're really looking...
They definitely noticed.
I completely missed my chance to say hi.
完全に挨拶のタイミング
逃したなあ…
気まずいなあ…
This is awkward.
でも立場的には
私から行かないとなんだよなあ…
But since I'm less important,
I have to greet them first.
Alright!
よし！
って もう来てるじゃん！
She's already here!
（ゴリ･烈子）あっ…
あの…
-Um...
（ゴリ）やっぱり
同じ会社の人よね？
（烈子）
会社で よく お見かけしますよね？
We see each other at work a lot, don't we?
（ゴリ･烈子）あっ…
Oh...
（烈子）アハハ…
（ゴリ）あら やだ…
-Oh...
-Oh, dear...
（ゴリ･烈子）あの…
-Um...
（烈子）経理部の烈子と申しま…
（ゴリ）マーケ部のゴリと申しま…
I'm Retsuko, from Accounting.
（ゴリ･烈子）ハア…
I'm Washimi, from Secretarial.
（鷲美(わしみ)）秘書課の鷲美です
彼女は マーケ部のゴリちゃん
She's Gori, from Marketing.
You're the girl we see a lot at work.
会社で よく お見かけする子よね？
よろしく
It's nice to see you.
あっ…
よろしくお願いします！
It's nice to see you!
（携帯電話の着信音）
（スー）
あっ 烈子？ あの話 聞いた？
Oh, Retsuko? Did you hear?
何？
What?
Those two got back together
and are super in love now!
（スー）あの２人 またヨリ戻して
今 ラブラブだって
えー 何それ？
Huh? That's crazy.
それって ３万払ったかい
あったってことかな
I guess it was worth it
to give them 30,000 yen after all.
（スー）アハハハ… そうかもねー
You could be right!
Subtitle translation: John Haguewood
♪～
～♪